<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Fancy Blog</title>
    <link>https://mustafa.paltun.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My Fancy Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 22:59:57 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mustafa.paltun.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Joe Armstrong hates shared state?</title>
      <link>https://mustafa.paltun.net/post/why-joe-armstrong-hates-shared-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 22:59:57 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mustafa.paltun.net/post/why-joe-armstrong-hates-shared-state/</guid>
      <description>I stumbled across an awesome quote by Joe Armstrong when he was explaining the reason why he hates threads and shared state on a Hacker News Thread (It was an email conversation actually):
 In distributed systems there is no real shared state (imagine one machine in the USA another in Sweden) where is the shared state? In the middle of the Atlantic? - shared state breaks laws of physics. State changes are propagated at the speed of light - we always know how things were at a remote site not how they are now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is this blog about?</title>
      <link>https://mustafa.paltun.net/post/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:36:24 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mustafa.paltun.net/post/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>I am planning to use this blog to create my own event log about software to record things like ideas come up my mind, conclusions of my evaluations, takeaways after reading materials (books, blogs), explanations about how things work, sentences worth to remember and finally things that I always forget and re-google.
Some examples:
  Do not use the private key for encryption! Only for signing! Use the public key for encryption and the private key for decryption!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://mustafa.paltun.net/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 23:19:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mustafa.paltun.net/about/</guid>
      <description>I write software. Mostly server software. Mostly in Java. I am originally from Istanbul but currently living in Finland.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>